

Curriculum Vitae

Name: Viet Cuong Nguyen / Cuong Nguyen

Address: Kieler Straße 395 22525, Hamburg, Germany

E-Mail: cuong.nguyen.viet2991@gmail.com

Phone: +49 15203957579

About me:

 Have experience in object-oriented programming, functional programming, and web development. Good programming knowledge and open and joy to quickly get used to new technologies

- Affinity with architectures, micro-services
- Advocate of Clean Code
- Successful working in both team and self-directed settings.
- Fluent English and basic German

Education:

Jun 2012 - Jan 2015 RMIT University Vietnam

Bachelor of Information Technology Major - Application Programming

GPA 3.63 / 4.00 (Australian grade scale)

Oct 2015 - Oct 2019 UHH - Universität Hamburg

MSc. Intelligent Adaptive System

GPA 1.88 / 1.00 (German grade scale)

Work Experience / Internship:

Oct 2014 - Jan 2015 CSC Viet Nam, Exceed J project

Associate Java Developer

- Front-end developer for a web application used in the insurance industry.
- Responsible for functionality and unit testing.
- Responsible for performance optimization using AJAX Dynatrace.
- Responsible for fixing simple user interface and functionality bugs.
- Trained on the following technology: JavaServer Faces, PrimeFaces, jQuery.

Feb 2020 - Dec 2020 data42 Gmbh, GOOSE project

Web Developer, Full-stack

- Full-stack developer for the GOOSE project at data42
- Functional programming, Clojure, Clojurescript, micro-services
- Conception and development of large systems in the web environment with microservices and apis
- Visualization of data and relationships, and development of forward-looking user experience
- Support in the requirement, conception, and implementation of products and solutions

Course Completed:

Oct 2013 - Dec 2013 Software Engineering - Process & Tools

Team Leader

- Designed and built a *Restaurant Point-Of-Sale System* in a team of 5 using Java, Swing and Agile development method.
- Organized and facilitated daily reports, task distributions as well as weekly meetings with clients as Team Leader.
- Paired-programming with team members.

Jun 2014 - Aug 2014

Software Engineering - Design and Implementation

Team Leader

- Designed and built a *Texas Holdem Poker* game with client/server architecture.
- Applied Networking Socket and Multi-Threaded programming for client/server architecture and game implementation.
- Paired-programming with team members.

Oct 2017 - Mar 2018

Human-Robot Interaction Master Project

Team Member

- Team member of a group of 8 students working with a humanoid robot (NICO).
- Responsible for the vision module of the robot object recognition. Co-author of the publication "Designing a Personality-Driven Robot for a Human-Robot Interaction Scenario". International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA) 2019.

Mar 2019 - Sep 2019

Master Thesis

- "Reinforcement Learning as Strategy for Engaging Task-oriented Dialogue Systems".
- Using Reinforcement Learning to interweave contents of a task-oriented and a chit-chat dialogue system.

Skills:

Language:

English - IELTS 8.0

German - Goethe-Zertifikat B1

Technology: Python, Java, Clojure, Html, Javascript, CSS

AJAX, Rest, Graphql

SQLite, MySQL, PostgreSQL

Object-Oriented Programming, Functional Programming

Software Engineering / Software Architecture

Data processing, data analyst, data visualization, ML

Github: franknvc.github.io